# Matthew Incardona

UX Engineer, Entrepeneur

#### Personal Info

## **Email**

mpi7253@rit.edu

## Cell

631-371-7358

#### Links

matthewincardona.com

linkedin.com/in/matthew-incardona

#### Software

- Illustrator
- Photoshop
- Figma
- VS Code
- macOS, Windows, Linux

## **UX/UI Design**

- · Lean UX
- Prototyping
- User research
- · Web & mobile design

#### Front-End Dev.

- HTML5
- · CSS3
- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- Electron

#### Back-End Dev.

- CPanel
- MySQL
- PHP
- NodeJS

Passionate entrepreneur with over 4 years of experience as a freelance web designer, bringing together design and development knowledge to help businesses build client-centric experiences and grow their presence online. Skilled in project planning and team management. Currently looking for a coop for Spring 2023, Summer 2023.

## **Experience**

### March 2021 -Present

# Co-Founder, UX Engineer

Second Desk LLC - Stony Brook, NY

- Designing and developing a business-facing desktopas-a-service product in an Agile, multidisciplinary team.
- Designing high-fidelity prototypes for UI solutions using Figma and presenting them for team feedback.
- Developing a cross-platform, WebRTC-enabled remote desktop app using Electron.
- Conducting product research, creating user personas, and building competitive analysis matrices.

### July 2018 -Present

# Founder, Web Designer

DouxDolci Web Design - Stony Brook, NY

- Working directly with a variety of clients to design, build, and host custom WordPress websites.
- Balancing client expectations with their available budget and projected timeline to ensure the project fits their needs.
- Optimizing website performance, including using modern image formats, CDNs, and code minification.
- Managing an in-house web hosting solution for clients.

# May 2021 -August 2021

# **UX/UI Designer, Front-End Developer**

Bubble Meets, San Francisco, CA

- Worked with a startup developing innovative video conferencing software.
- Served as a bridge between the design and development teams and worked along the entire feature pipeline.
- Followed Lean UX process to create user-centric feature prototypes and user flows using Figma.
- Converted prototypes into re-usable React code for the product website and video conferencing app.

#### Education

# BS in Human-Centered Computing, 3.77 GPA

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY

Transfer student, expected graduation date May 2024